# Jinhyuk Yoon

#### **POSTECH, Haptics and Virtual Reality Laboratory**

Rooms 011, Science Building 4, 77 Cheongam-Ro, Nam-Gu, Pohang, Gyeongbuk, Korea

jinhyukyoon@postech.ac.kr https://www.jinhyukyoon.com

I am an interaction designer and engineer building interactive experience through physical touch and manipulation. To broaden insight and contextual understanding for human-computer interaction, I have been participating in research, industrial and start-up business, education, talk, performance and art work. Through technological and humanistic point of view, I have been trying to create meaningful experience.

## **Professional Experience**

**Geekble** Mar 2019 – Present

**Communications Manager** 

Designing contents for interactive education business which provide playful and empirical knowledge related to science and engineering.

#### **POSTECH, Haptics and Virtual Reality Laboratory**

Feb 2019 - Present

Research Intern

Developing a pneumatic haptic device to provide interactive tactile experiences.

#### Samsung Electronics, Digital Appliances Division, Core Component R&D Lab

Jan 2019 – Feb 2019

Mechanical Design Intern

Analyzed mechanical property of spring and damper hinge mounted in oven door. Deployed the analysis result on interactive data platform to simplify design process.

**Sovoro** Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

Communications Manager

Conducted UI/UX research and design of the service, catalog design, and market research. Engaged in business activity related with public institution, educational institution, and people with hearing loss.

#### Korea Foundation for the Advancement of Science & Creativity

May 2016 - Jan 2018

Science Communicator

Gave talk, performed science street performance, and acted science play only for adults as a finalist of the FameLab Korea and a science communicator commissioned by minister of Ministry of Science & ICT.

#### Asan Medical Center, Biomedical Engineering Research Center

Aug 2017 - Sep 2017

Research Intern

Designed concept prototype of Ankle Rehabilitation Assistant which analyzes ankle torque and provides rehabilitative movement.

## **Leadership Experience**

#### **POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering**

Jan 2016 - Mar 2017

**Student President** 

Directed student membership training, professor appreciation banquet, association program with KAIST and founded basketball and badminton club.

#### **POSTECH, Student Election Committee**

Sep 2016 - Nov 2016

Chairman

Organized the student election committee and run the election for central student president.

TEDxPOSTECH Nov 2014 – Nov 2015

Director

Organized TEDx event under the theme 'question' with 6 speakers. Regular application was fully booked in 50 seconds after opening. Conducted team building, speaker and sponsor contact, stage planning and host at the event.

## **Education**

### **Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering**

2014 - Present

Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH)

Minor in Industrial management engineering. Expect to graduate with *Magna Cum Laude* 

### **Awards and Honors**

The 2<sup>nd</sup> POSTECH Hackathon

| <b>Commission Letter</b> Minister of Ministry of Science & ICT commissioned me as a science communicator | 2016       |
|--|------------|
| <b>Finalist</b> Nationwide Top 11 of the 3 <sup>rd</sup> FameLab Korea                                   | 2016       |
| <b>Runners up</b> Artience Creation Challenge 30x30 hosted by British Council                            | 2017       |
| Honorable Mention 3 Minutes Science Speech Contest hosted by POSTECH                                     | 2015       |
| Student of the Year POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering  | 2015, 2016 |
| The 4 <sup>th</sup> Prize  | 2016       |

| National Academic Excellence Scholarship Korea Student Aid Foundation | 2016 – Present |
|---|----------------|
| KT&G Foundation Scholarship POSTECH                                   | 2016           |
| Jigok Scholarship POSTECH   | 2014 - 2016    |

## **Skills and Tools**

### **Programming Language**

C, C++, JAVA, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MATLAB

### **Graphic Design**

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, After Effects, InDesign

### **3D Design & Analysis**

Solidworks, NX

## **Selected Talks**

| Keynote Speech, "About Experience", POSTECH Alumni Conference for Freshman, Pohang                                       | 2018 |
|--|------|
| Keynote Speech, "Engineering and Science Communication", The 5th Integrated Science Leading Teacher Training, Yeongcheon | 2016 |
| Keynote Speech, "About Science Communicαtion", National Youth Science Exploration Competition, Gyeongju                  | 2016 |
| Talk, "Regain the lost life", Suseong-gu Gosan Library, Daegu  | 2018 |
| Talk, "Regain the lost life", KIST Science Station, Seoul  | 2017 |
| Talk, "Space food", The 13th Bohyeonsan Starlight Festival, Yeongcheon   | 2016 |
| Talk, "Science, Engineering and Me", Seongji Highschool, Yongin  | 2017 |
| Talk, "Communicate with Science", Mulgeum High School, Yangsan   | 2017 |
| Talk, "Talk with Odd Engineering Student", Samsung Girl's High School, Busan   | 2017 |